Mobile Suit
Rage on! Rage on! Rage on! Gundam!
Moeagare! Moeagare! Moeagare GANDAMU!
You must run forth!
Kimi yo hashire
If you are still burning with furious rage...
Mada ikari ni moeru toshi ga aru nara...
You must fight the towering foe!
Kyodai na teki o
Fight! Fight! Fight!
Uteyo! Uteyo! Uteyo!
Bring to bear the rage of justice, Gundam
Seigi no ikari o butsukero GANDAMU
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
Rise once more! Rise once more!
Yomigaeru! Yomigaeru!
Rise once more! Gundam!
Yomigaeru GANDAMU!
You must seize the power!
Kimi yo tsukame
Fly toward the galaxy, Gundam!
Ginga e mukatte tobeyo GANDAMU
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
But the Federation Forces have exhausted
their fighting strength.
In other words, they lack the strength
to take out Granada or A Baoa Qu.
As a result, they'll probably
Invade our homeland directly.
That's the sort of thing Revil would plan.
That's all the more reason why
we must try to avoid further warfare.
That's what the Solar Ray Is for.
I'll wipe out the Federation
with one blow, Father.
There's no way he can do it... Right, Garma?
Seeking to defuse a situation that was
no longer under his control Sovereign Degwin
...departed from the Principality of Zeon.
Supreme Commander Gihren Zabi,
of course, had not been informed.
A Cosmic Glow
You've grown old, Father.
It's already too late...
What is it?
Call from Captain Asakura,
the technical advisor.
All right. Put him through.
Reporting, sir.
The Solar Ray is now operational.
Good.
It'll reach critical point in two hours.
But, sir...
Go on.
Sir.
We had to use the critically permeable
membranes and polarized mirrors...
...that were created for testing purposes.
As a result, the Solar Ray system
can be fired only once.
Are its capabilities as we predicted?
Yes.
A 3-second continuous irradiation...
...and an angle adjustment of
up to 12 degrees in that time.
I am impressed.
The preparations must be flawless.
Repairs to the Gelgoog should be finished
within 20 to 30 minutes.
Once that's done,
we'll commence our second wave of attacks.
Yes, ma'am.
After we defeat the Trojan Horse's group,
we'll head immediately for A Baoa Qu.
Our intelligence indicates that Revil's
main fleet will ignore Granada.
Oh?
But first, there's something
I want to ask you.
What made you abandon your plans
to overthrow the Zabi family?
My... plans?
I spent some time playing with young Casval
when he was about four years old...
Have you forgotten?
Ever since you summoned me,
Lady Kycilia...
...I knew that a time like this would come.
But it doesn't make it any less frightening...
My hand won't stop shaking.
I felt the same way...
when I found out about your identity.
And how did you...?
It was Lalah.
You had sent Lalah to the Flanagan Institute.
I realized that you had
almost clairvoyant insight...
...so I ordered a thorough investigation.
Lalah made you believe
in the existence of Newtypes...
...and you now have greater goals
than overthrowing the Zabi family.
Correct...
Gihren has taken command
at A Baoa Qu.
Yes, ma'am.
Everything else will be dealt with
after we defeat the Federation. Understood?
Yes... Of course.
Newtypes, huh...
So they're different from espers?
Right.
But judging from what Amuro said,
the enemy must have superhuman abilities.
For now, let's assume so.
There's no way we can possibly fight
against an enemy like that.
But I don't think it's that serious.
Sorry about this, Amuro,
but if that Tricorn Hat appears again...
Of course I'll take care of it...
At this point, I have no choice.
That's true. Right now, you're exhibiting
Newtype potential, Amuro.
That's the only logical explanation
for everything that's happening.
Inside of me...
Good luck.
But even if I am a Newtype,
I'm not special!
With the way we've been fighting, I think
all the White Base crew must be Newtypes!
Otherwise, we couldn't have made it this far.
You may have a point there...
But I still sense something
extraordinary about you, Amuro.
Y-Yes. I won't deny it.
I've been especially convinced
since encountering that Tricorn Hat...
And... that "la... la" sound.
Captain! We're in diamond formation!
Good! Now hurry up and send out
all the mobile suit teams.
Sir!
We'll stage an all-out assault on the fleet.
The goal is to sink at least half the vessels.
After that, you'll deal with the Gundam.
Yes, sir.
I'll head out in the Gelgoog, but this time
I'll be following your orders, Lalah.
Captain...!
You've surpassed me now, Lalah.
Captain...
From now on, I want you to wear
your normal suit whenever you sortie.
If you say so.
Thank you very much...
Mobile suit launching complete!
Assault formation assumed
with Captain Char's Zanzibar in the lead!
Good!
We'll hold here in the Gwazine.
30 seconds after Captain Char launches,
give him 30 seconds of covering fire!
Enemy vessels are on the move!
They're passing the F-line!
Mr. Kai! Hayato!
Time to launch!
What about shifts?
Let's leave things in their hands.
Newtypes, huh...?
Fraw Bow! Make sure they launch quickly!
Yes!
What is it?
N-Nothing.
Hey, Amuro!
Darn it, Amuro!
30 seconds! Fire!
I hope they'll be okay! We'd better have
a place to return to!
Incoming!
10 degrees starboard, at 1:30!
They're gonna change their course!
Four ships coming up portside!
Put up a barrage!
Don't stop!
Two vessels down on each side!
The enemy's started evasive action!
Right! Anti-air fire!
They'll send in the mobile suits next!
Here they come!
They're in teams of 5 or 6. I see at least 15!
You...!
Why you...!
Here comes the Tricorn Hat!
I get it! The control...!
I can sense it!
La... la...
A... mu... ro!
Lalah...?
Why are you fighting, Lalah?
Because you'll hurt Char.
What?
You're a bad person, trying to harm Char!
Th-That's crazy!
The strength you're displaying tells me...
...if I don't defeat you, Char will die!
Char?! ...S-So that's why!
I'm afraid you arrived too late!
Too late...?
Why... Why did you have to appear now?
Why...? How can this be?
How can you keep fighting like this?!
You have no one to defend
and nothing to protect, and yet...!
I have nothing to protect?!
I can see that...
...there's no family in your heart.
And no homeland either.
So what's your point?!
Mobile Suit
Gundam
I'm gonna get you!
Is it wrong of me to fight
if I have nothing to defend?
It's unnatural.
Then what are you doing, Lalah?!
I'm fighting for the one person
who saved me.
That's it... There's nothing else?!
Yes... It's a truth that one lives for.
Does it mean nothing that we met?!
Was this...
Amuro, was this destiny?
Yes... I believe so.
I think this was destiny!
But why? Why?!
If this is fate... then life is just too cruel!
But we have to accept it.
Lalah, open your eyes.
Really? Could you really be right?
Is it fate, as you say?
Lalah!
Amuro!
Amuro! Don't do it!
But... why now?!
Why now, of all times?!
Because we're all burdened
with our own fate.
Lalah! Stop fooling around with him!
Char...!
There...!
My brother!
Brother! Please pull back!
It's too dangerous! Stay back, Ms. Sayla!
Brother, it's me! Can't you tell?
Lalah! I need to crush that Gundam!
Give your guidance!
Lalah!
I'll help you...
I'll help you, Captain.
Thank you, Lalah!
Char!!
I'm not going to let you take Lalah away!
Can I...?
Captain, you're too close!
Ms. Sayla?!
Captain! No!
It's Artesia!
Char! You're finished!
Captain!
Lalah!!
Lalah...!
Lalah!!!
People are changing...
They're becoming like us.
Yeah. That's true.
You're right about that, Lalah.
Amuro, do you honestly believe that?
Of course I believe it!
You and I were able
to understand each other!
One day people will even
be able to control time...
Oh, Amuro!
I can see time itself...
I'll spread my wings and embrace you
tsubasa wo hirogete anata wo dakuwa
I wonder if you'll be lonely tomorrow
ashita anata wa sabishii kashira
We do not feel such things
sonna koto nai watashitachi
So please sleep now, Amuro
dakara ne oyasumi Amuro
If the two of us should leave the nest
konna futari ga sudatsu tomo
The sadness is endless, endless
tada kanashimi ga hatenakute hatenakute
We yearn
akogareru
A dream, it is a dream, a dream
yume sore wa yume yume
Tomorrow, we will both be bloodsoaked
ashita futari wa chimidoro de
Dancing in the wind, the wind, the wind
kaze ni kaze ni kaze ni mau
La... Lalah...
I've done something terrible...
I've done something I can never take back!
Get the Zanzibar!
Concentrate all fire on the Zanzibar!
Just get the Trojan Horse! Just that ship!
So the Gwazine is our only remaining ship.
How pathetic.
I agree.
The Gundam pilot's Newtype abilities...
...are becoming even greater.
It's overwhelming...
Lady Kycilia, we've received orders from
Supreme Commander Gihren at A Baoa Qu.
Oh?
The Federation's main fleet
Is heading for A Baoa Qu.
All Zeon fleets In the Solar Ray's firing path
are to retreat immediately.
The operation will commence at 21:05.
Are you telling me...
They're using the Solar Ray in 30 minutes?!
The Solar Ray?
They're going to use it?
It's too rash...
What's Gihren plotting?
We're going to be late to the rendezvous
with the main fleet.
Mirai. Can the Salamis behind us keep up?
I doubt it. Let's go on ahead.
But will they be okay?
There are no more Zeons in this airspace,
so they'll be fine.
Besides, the Newtype that challenged Amuro
is no more.
Don't worry. I can still fight.
Right, Haro? I'm doing fine, aren't I?
Amuro, brainwave level excellent!
Excellent!
Thanks.
In the meantime...
The Earth Federation fleet,
led by General Revil...
...was gathering at the third battle line
leading to A Baoa Qu.
It was at this point that General Revil
announced their target.
They were to fight past A Baoa Qu,
and invade the Zeon homeland.
The Great Degwin has arrived
for peace negotiations.
But at that very moment...
This is Gihren speaking from A Baoa Qu.
I will now announce the final target
of the Solar Ray system.
The main forces of the enemy's Revil Fleet...
...are split into three groups.
But if we aim the Solar Ray at Gel Dorva...
...we should be able to take out
a third of their forces.
Solar Ray system...
...stand by!
Roger that, sir!
Solar Ray system, stand by!
Generator systems: no problems!
Microwave transmitters: operational!
Output: 8500 gigawatts per hour!
Adjust firing angle... down 012, right 0032!
Primary target is Gel Dorva!
Musai over generator system 825! Clear out!
Your shadow will lower our output!
No! Don't do it! Don't move forward!
People are melting in a whirlpool of light!
That's the light of hatred!
Will the rivalry between Gihren and Kycilia
drive Zeon into a crisis?
The surviving members of the Earth
Federation Forces stage their final assault.
Char, too, makes a stand.
And Amuro almost seems
to follow Lalah's fate.
Mobile Suit Gundam. Next episode...
Space Fortress: A Baoa Qu
Will you be able to survive?
Next Time
Space Fortress: A Baoa Qu
Amuro, do not look back
The star shining far off in space...
Amuro, it's your homeland where you were born
Do you remember the days of your childhood?
The morning when you woke up in warmth?
Amuro, do not look back, Amuro...
A man must hide his tears, hide his tears
Only look to tomorrow, to tomorrow forever...